mo She slept a long time, and when she awakened Mrs. Medlock had bought a lunch
basket at one of the stations and they had some chicken and cold beef and bread
and butter and some hot tea. The rain seemed to be streaming down
more heavily than ever and everybody in the station wore wet and glistening
waterproofs. The guard lighted the lamps in the carriage, and Mrs. Medlock cheered
up very much over her tea and chicken and beef. She ate a great deal and
afterward fell asleep herself, and Mary sat and stared at her and watched her
fine bonnet slip on one side until she herself fell asleep once more in the
corner of the carriage, lulled by the splashing of the rain against the
windows. It was quite dark when she awakened again. The train had stopped at
a station and Mrs. Medlock was shaking her. "You have had a sleep!" she said. "It's
time to open your eyes! We're at TH Station and we've got a long drive before us."
Mary stood up and tried to keep her eyes open while Mrs. Medlock collected her
parcels. The little girl did not offer to help her, because in India native
servants always picked up or carried things and it seemed quite proper that
other people should wait on one. The station was a small one and
nobody but themselves seemed to be getting out of the train. The station Master spoke to Mrs.
Medlock in a rough, good-natured way, pronouncing his words in a queer broad
fashion which Mary found out afterward was Yorkshire. "I see that's got back," he said
and th brought the young with thee I that's her," answered Mrs. Medlock,
speaking with a Yorkshire accent herself and jerking her head over her shoulder
toward Mary. "How's thy Miss Well now the carriage is waiting outside for
thee." A brew stood on the road before the little outside
platform. Mary saw that it was a smart carriage and that it was a smart footman
who helped her in. His long waterproof coat and the waterproof covering of his
hat was shining and dripping with rain as everything was, the burly station Master
included. When he shut the door, mounted the box with the coachman, and they drove
off, the little girl girl found herself seated in a comfortably cushioned corner,
but she was not inclined to go to sleep again. She sat and looked out of the
window, curious to see something of the road over which she was being driven to
the queer place Mrs. Medlock had spoken of. She was not at all a timid child and
she was not exactly frightened, but she felt that there was no knowing what
might happen in a house with a h hundred rooms nearly all shut up— —a house
standing on the edge of a Moore What is a Moore she said suddenly to Mrs.
Medlock. "Look out of the window in about 10 minutes and you'll see," the woman
answered. "We've got to drive 5 miles across mistl Moore before we get to the
Mana You won't see much because it's a dark night, but you can see
something." Mary asked no more questions but waited in the darkness of her corner,
keeping her eyes on the window. The carriage lamps cast rays of
light a little distance ahead of them and she caught glimpses of the things
they passed. After they had left the station they had driven through a tiny
village and she had seen whitewashed cottages and the lights of a public
house. Then they had passed a church and a vicarage and a little shop window or
so in a cottage with toys and suits and odd things set out for sale.
Then they were on the high road and she saw hedges and trees. After that there seemed nothing
different for a long time— —or at least it seemed a long time to
her. At last the horses began to go more slowly, as if they were climbing
uphill and presently there seemed to be no more hedges and no more
trees. She could see nothing, in fact, but a dense darkness on the side. She leaned
forward and pressed her face against the window just as the carriage gave a big
jolt. "Eh! We're on the mo now sure enough," said Mrs.
Medlock. The carriage lamps shed a yellow light on a rough looking road which
seemed to be cut through bushes and low growing things which ended in the great
expanse of dark apparently spread out before and around them. A wind was rising
and making a singular, wild, low, rushing sound. "It's— —it's not the sea, is it?" said
Mary, looking round at her companion. "No, not it," answered Mrs. Medlock.
"Nor it isn't fields nor mountains, it's just miles and miles and miles of wild
land that nothing grows on but heather and gors and broom, and nothing lives on
but wild ponies and sheep." "I feel as if it might be the sea, if there were water
on it," said Mary. "It sounds like the sea just now." "That's the wind blowing through
the bushes," Mrs. Medlock said. "It's a wild, dreary enough place to my mind, though
there's plenty that likes it— —particularly when the Heathers in
bloom." On and on they drove through the darkness, and though the rain stopped, the
wind rushed by and whistled and made strange sounds. The road went up and down,
and several times the carriage passed over a little bridge beneath which water
rushed very fast with a great deal of noise. Mary felt as if the drive would
never come to an end and that the wide, bleak Moore was a wide expanse of black
ocean through which she was passing on a strip of dry
land. "I don't like it," she said to herself. "I don't like it," and she pinched
her thin lips more tightly together. The horses were climbing up a hilly piece of
road when she first caught sight of a light. Mrs. Medlock saw it as soon as she
did and drew a long sigh of relief a I am glad to see that bitter
light twinkling," she exclaimed. "It's the light in the lodge window. We shall get a
good cup of tea after a bit, at all events." It was "after a bit," as she said,
for when the carriage passed through the park gates there was still 2 miles of
avenue to drive through and the trees (which nearly met overhead) made it seem
as if they were driving through a long dark vault. They drove out of the vault into a
clear space and stopped before an immensely long but low-built house which
seemed to ramble around a stone court. At first Mary thought that there
were no lights at all in the windows, but as she got out of the carriage she saw
that one room in a corner upstairs showed a dull glow. The entrance door was a huge one
made of massive, curiously shaped panels of oak studded with big iron nails and
bound with great iron bars. It opened into an enormous hall, which was so dimly lighted that the
faces in the portraits on the walls and the figures in the suits of armor made
Mary feel that she did not want to look at
them. As she stood on the stone floor she looked a very small, odd little black
figure, and she felt as small and lost and odd as she looked. A neat, thin old
man stood near the manservant who opened the door for
them. "You are to take her to her room," he
said in a husky voice. "He doesn't want to see her. He's going to London in the
morning." "Very well, Mr. Pitcher," Mrs. Medlock answered So long as as I know what's
expected of me, I can manage." "What's expected of you, Mrs.
Medlock," Mr. Pitcher said, "is that you make sure that he's not disturbed and that he
doesn't see what he doesn't want to see." And then Mary Lennox was led up a
broad staircase and down a long corridor and up a short flight of steps and
through another corridor and another, until a door opened in a wall and she
found herself in a room with a fire in it and a supper on a
table. Mrs. Medlock said unceremoniously: "Well, here you are! This
room and the next are where you'll live— —and you must keep to them. Don't you forget
that!" It was in this way Mistress Mary arrived at mleth Manor and she had
perhaps never felt quite so contrary in all her life